The JSDF was dispatched to the Special Region.
特地に派遣された自衛隊
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
Having traveled to Japan for a testimony at the Diet,
参考人招致のため　日本に戻った伊丹たちだったが
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 www.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
Itami and the others returned beyond the gate.
役目を終え　再び特地へと向かうことに
日听 Keishin Cc  翻译 domi  Akashi   校对 はばやし  小伍  时间轴 神埼魯蒙  压制 咸鱼
As they crossed the gate,
they were seen off by a huge crowd
その時　群衆からは割れんばかりの歓声と　拍手が降り注いだのであった
and rapturous cheers.
And now...
そして
almost five months have passed since Japan and the Empire began hostilities.
日本と帝国が開戦して　五ヶ月は経とうとしていた
After the battle of Italica,
イタリカの戦い以降　アルヌス周辺はいたって平穏であった
Alnus was extremely peaceful.
Alnus  Refugee Camp
As different cultures and goods began to mingle in the shadow of the gate,
「門」を介しての人的物的交流が盛んになるにつれ
many different people began to gather in Alnus,
アルヌスには様々な人々が集うようになり
and little by little, the area around the refugee camp developed into a town.
避難民キャンプの周辺には　少しずつ町ができていた
Meanwhile, Piña Co Lada, who had seen Japan for herself,
一方　自分の目で日本を見てきたピニャ・コ・ラーダは
講和への決意を胸に　帝都へと帰還した
returned to the capital, hoping to bring about peace.
Accompanying her was Sugawara Kouji,
an envoy of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.
彼女には外務省から派遣された菅原浩治が同行
Secret negotiations were about to begin.
水面下での交渉が始まろうとしていた
Your plans today are lunch with Lord Cicero,
本日の予定はキケロ卿との午餐
and a dinner party with Count Dussie.
デュシー侯爵家で晩餐パーティー
As well as a meeting with Shandee between them.
その間に　シャンディーとの面談があります
Were you up all night again?
また徹夜ですか？
It's not good for you to push yourself so hard.
あまり無理をされると　お体に障りますよ
I know.
わかっている
However, the Empire's survival rests on making peace with Japan.
だが　二ホンとの講和には帝国の存亡がかかっているのだ
This is no time to worry about my health.
今は我が身を顧みている時ではない
What's this?
これは？
A list of prisoners whose return we're requesting.
返還を希望する捕虜の名簿です
Fourteen?
十四名？
There were supposed to be fifteen in the first group...
第一陣の転移は十五名だったはずだが
You're the one who wanted me to leave a slot open for Lord Cicero!
キケロ卿のために一名分空けておけとおっしゃったのは殿下ではありませんか
Oh...
ああ　そうか
You're right.
そうだったな
本当に大丈夫ですか？
Are you sure you're all right?
If I told you I wasn't, would you take over for me?
大丈夫じゃないといったら　代わってくれるか
I couldn't, no.
無理ですね
Then I'll just have to keep at it.
ならば　頑張るしかないだろう
Let's go. Sugawara is waiting.
行くぞ　スガワラ殿が待っている
So that's Alnus...
あれが　アルヌス
Thus, the JSDF Fought There!
to
kk
Thus, the JSDF Fought There!
u
ni
Thus, the JSDF Fought There!
na
to
ni
I don't really have anything I'm wishing for
Thus, the JSDF Fought There!
特に何も望むことなんてない　身の程は知っているさ
mo
no
kk
zo
to
u
mu
kk
ko
ni
to
u
na
n
te
na
i
ni
na
mo
ni
no
mo
zo
no
mu
zo
ko
mu
to
ko
na
to
n
na
te
n
na
te
i
na
mi
no
ho
do
wa
mi
i
sh
I pretty much know my place.
i
t
te
i
no
ru
mi
sa
ho
no
do
ho
wa
do
sh
wa
i
sh
t
i
te
t
i
te
ru
i
sa
ru
so
n
na
bo
ku
so
sa
de
Even so, I think deep down that I don't wanna let anything go
sa
そんな僕でさえも奥の方に
e
om
n
ou
so
o
ku
no
na
ho
n
u
ni
bo
na
ku
bo
de
ku
sa
de
e
sa
om
e
ou
om
o
ou
ku
o
no
ku
ho
no
u
ho
ni
u
yu
zu
ri
ta
ni
It seems I'm only playing "the good girl".
ku
yu
na
譲りたくない　意向程度はあるらしい
i
ii
ko
tte
zu
i
yu
to
ha
a
ru
ra
sh
i
ri
zu
ta
ri
ku
ta
na
ku
i
na
ii
i
ko
ii
tte
ko
i
tte
to
i
ha
to
a
ha
ru
a
ra
ru
sh
ra
i
sh
ma
mo
ru
t
i
Protecting something is harder than I thought,
te
ma
an
ga
i
to
守るって案外と難しいね
mu
mo
zu
ma
ka
sh
i
ru
ne
mo
t
ru
te
t
an
te
ga
an
i
ga
to
i
mu
to
zu
mu
ka
zu
sh
ka
i
sh
ne
i
a
ki
ra
ne
But it's not like that means I'm gonna give up!
me
ru
a
wa
ke
ja
諦めるわけじゃないけど
na
i
ke
ki
do
a
ra
ki
me
ra
ru
me
wa
ru
ke
wa
ja
ke
na
ja
i
na
ke
i
do
ke
ao
i
so
ra
no
ao
ha
At the far reaches of the blue sky - the end of these connected roads,
te
t
su
na
青い空の果て　繋がった道の行方
ga
t
i
ta
ao
mi
chi
no
yu
ku
e
so
i
ra
so
no
ra
ha
no
te
ha
t
te
su
t
na
su
ga
na
t
ga
ta
t
mi
ta
chi
mi
no
chi
yu
no
ku
yu
e
ku
hi
to
wa
e
People still won't come to understand one another... but I'm fine with that
wa
ka
ri
a
人と人は分かり合えない　だけどいいんじゃない？
to
e
hi
na
i
da
ke
do
ii
n
to
ja
na
i
hi
to
wa
ka
ri
a
e
na
i
da
ke
do
ii
n
ja
na
The door I'll open will have everything changing,
i
na
hi
ra
i
ta
to
hi
bi
i
ra
hi
開いた扉は全てを変えてゆく
wa
su
be
te
i
o
ra
ka
e
ta
te
i
yu
ku
to
ta
bi
to
ra
bi
wa
ra
su
wa
be
su
te
be
o
te
ka
o
e
ka
te
e
yu
te
ku
yu
so
re
wa
a
ka
so
ku
t
Just like the break of dawn!
su
それは暁のように
re
ki
so
no
yo
u
ni
wa
re
a
wa
ka
a
t
ka
su
t
ki
su
no
ki
yo
no
u
yo
ni
u
Episode 11  Visitor
This is going to upset my stomach.
これは胃にくるな
I told you that you'd need more than one stomach for this.
だから言ったであろう　胃袋がいくつあっても足りんと
You were right.
確かに　国からいい胃薬を取り寄せましょう
I'll get some good stomach medicine from home.
That would be great!
それは助かる
Cicero La Martos.
キケロ・ラー・マルトゥス
The Martos clan has been one of the Empire's most important families throughout its history,
帝国開闢以来の名門　マルトゥス家の一族にして
and he has tremendous influence in the Senate.
元老院に広く顔の利く重臣
He's also, of the hawks, one of the ones more willing to talk.
そして　主戦派の中では話せる御仁だ
After the annihilation at Alnus,
アルヌスでの壊滅的な敗戦ののち
the Empire's army is rebuilding.
帝国軍は再建の途上にあるわけだが
The Senate is split on which of two directions it should go.
その方向性を巡って今　元老院が二つに割れている
一つは　皇帝の大権のもとに　総力を結集し
One group is the Imperial faction,
which wants to gather all our forces under the Emperor's authority
武力をもって　蛮族を排除しようという主戦派
and wipe out the barbarians.
And the other is the Senatorial faction, which wants peace?
もう一方は　元老院の大半をなす講和派
That's right.
そうだ
They seek to limit the Emperor's powers, as he was the one who started this reckless war.
彼らはこの無謀な戦争を始めた皇帝の力を制限し
They want the new military to answer to the Senate,
元老院の指揮下で軍を再建　その軍事力を背景に
so its might can be used...
...to persuade Japan to return beyond the gate peacefully.
二ホンと交渉し　戦火を交えることなく　門の向こうに帰らせようとしている
In other words, the doves...
つまり　講和派は
Yes.
ああ　奴らは工作などせずとも　こちらの話に乗ってくるということだ
They'll work with us without any additional effort required on our part.
As such, our first targets...
従って　われらがまず切り崩すべきは
主戦派だ
...are the hawks.
Lord Cicero,
キケロ卿
こちら　二ホン国の外交特使　スガワラ殿だ
this is Lord Sugawara, special ambassador from Japan.
Hello. I've come from Japan.
初めまして　日本からやって参りました　菅原です
My name is Sugawara.
I'm sorry, "Japan"?
はて　二ホン？
Sorry, but I've never heard of such a country.
失礼ながら　初めて聞く名だ
What is it like?
どのような国かね
Let me see...
そうですね　四季があり　森や水のきれいな国です
It's a beautiful country, with four seasons, forests, and clean water.
ほう　水が
Water, you say?
It must be a country with great natural beauty.
さぞや自然の豊かなところなのであろうな
I've brought some items from my country.
我が国の産物を持参しました
ご笑納いただければ　幸いです
I hope you'll accept them.
すべて　我が国の職人の手によるものです
These were all created by my country's craftsmen.
My apologies, Lord Sugawara.
失礼した　スガワラ殿
Your nation seems to be possessed of talented craftsmen,
貴殿の国は優れた技術をお持ちのようだ
and yet I've never heard of it in my life.
しかし　寡聞にして　聞き及んだことがない
Where is "Japan"?
二ホンとは　どこにあるのですかな
我が国は門の向こうにございます
Our nation lies beyond the gate.
Unfortunately, we are presently at war with the Empire...
残念ながら現在　帝国と戦争中でありますが
Princess Piña!
ピニャ殿下
Everyone, get out of the room!
みんな　部屋から出ていけ
I want to talk to them in private.
この者たちだけで話がしたい
What are you thinking?
どういうおつもりか
Meeting with an enemy in secret,
秘密裏に敵国と交渉し　あまつさえ使者まで招き入れるとは
and even bringing one of their messengers here?
If this is discovered,
ことが露見すれば　皇女といえど　無事では済まされませんぞ
even being a princess won't save you.
Lord Sugawara!
スガワラ殿　貴殿もこのままで済むと思わんことだ
You're not going to escape, either!
これを
Here.
This is my nephew's name!
He was part of the expedition!
これは出征した甥の名
今は我が国で捕虜となっております
He is a prisoner in my country right now.
He's alive?
生きておるのか？
ええ　ピニャ殿下に仲介の労を担っていただく代わりに
Yes.
Princess Piña has offered to act as mediator
お返しする準備を進めております
in exchange for the prisoners' return.
And in exchange, you wish me to set up negotiations?
その代りに貴殿らを交渉のテーブルまで案内しろと
No, that's her job.
いいえ　それはピニャ殿下のお役目です
I see.
なるほど　邪魔をするなということか
So you want me to stay out of her way?
I'm going to deliver good news to the Dussie family tonight.
妾は今宵　デュシー家に良き知らせを届けることになっている
Why don't you join me?
卿も同席されてはいかがか
The Dussie family?
デュシー家　確かあそこにも出征した者がおりましたな
I believe they sent family on the expedition, as well.
I'll be happy to go.
喜んでご相席させていただきましょう
And I hope you'll remember my nephew...
ついては　我が甥もよしなに
It's sure gotten more lively around here.
ここらも随分とにぎやかになったねえ
It started as a PX for the refugees
難民用のＰＸから始まり
and ended up as a small town.
気が付けば　ちょっとした町ですな
Anything we bring from Japan is going to be new to the people here,
こっちの人たちにとっては
日本から運ばれてくるものは何でも珍しいだろうから　不思議じゃないさ
so it makes sense.
I've heard that Imperial nobility have been enjoying the products sold here lately.
最近では　ここで仕入れたものが帝都の貴族の間でも珍重されているとか
I see.
なるほど
Well, nothing wrong with that.
ま　いいんじゃない
This stuff also makes great gifts for us to send back home, too.
こういうのが手に入ると　俺たちも土産にちょうどいいし
It's a good thing for both of us, right?
お互いにとって　悪いことじゃないでしょ
Not necessarily.
そうとも言い切れません
The sudden increase in the size of the town means that we're always short of people.
町の急速な発展に伴って　人手は常に不足しています
The only reason the place runs is because Myui-sama lends her maids.
この町が回っているのは
ミュイ様が快くメードたちを貸し出してくれたおかげです
It's a bad influence though.
ただ　それの弊害も
A bad influence?
弊害？
Some of the bars and restaurants where the maids work serve alcohol,
メードたちの働く飲食店には　酒類を出すところもあり
and some of our younger ones are becoming regulars.
うちの若い奴らがこうして足しげく通っているようでね
They need a break once in a while, right?
たまには息抜きも必要でしょう
Well, if they start going a bit too nuts, let them know.
ま　あんまり羽を外すようだったら　それとなく注意しといてよ
Right...
What are you doing?
何すんだい
Get the hell out!
一昨日来やがれ
My butt is too good for the likes of you!
このデリラ様の尻は　あんたみたいな三下が触れるほど安くはないんだよ
You little bitch—
てめぇ　調子に乗りやがって
I haven't seen you around here before.
あなた　見かけない顔だけどぉ
Do you know who I am?
私が誰だかお分かりかしらぁ
エエ…エムロイの…
The Priestess of Emloy...
If you want to play nice,
大人しくしてくれるのなら　このまま見逃してあげるけどぉ
I can let you go.
Or if you haven't had enough fighting,
暴れ足りないっていうなら　お相手するわよぉ
I can fight you.
I'm good, thanks!
け　結構でーす
Coward.
意気地なし
On patrol, Rory?
見回りか　ロゥリィ
There are so many people coming and going lately.
最近出入りする人数が増えたもんだから
Some of them are stupid like him. It's rough.
ああいうおバカさんも混じってて大変なのよぉ
ご苦労さん
Thanks for the help.
You here for dinner, Youji?
ヨウジは食事ぃ？
あいや　ちょっと呼び出されてな
No, I got called out here.
Here you go!
お待ち遠様
Tuka?
テュカ？
Tuka!
テュカぁ
Looking for someone?
誰か探してんのぉ？
Yeah, I guess you could say that.
ううん　ちょっとね
Could it be a man?
もしかして男？
違う違う
No, no.
Is she doing that every day?
まさか毎日なのか
Yes.
She wanders around town
このぐらいの時間になると　いるはずのない父親を捜して彷徨ってるのです
looking for her dead father every night.
いつまで放っておくつもりですか
How long will we let her do that?
I see where you're coming from, but...
そうはいってもな
Do we really need to force her to accept reality?
無理に現実を分からせる必要あるのかしら
あるに決まってます
Of course we do.
People can't live for the future without accepting reality.
人は現実を受け止めなければ　「明日」を生きられない
All she's doing now is wasting her present.
このままでは　彼女は「今」という時を消費するだけになってしまう
That's just not right.
それは厳しすぎます
That's true, but...
それはそうだけどぉ
Hey, Kurokawa. If we all got together and said,
なあ　黒川
俺たちが寄ってたかって　お前の父親は死んだんだって言ったら
"Tuka, your dad's dead,"
テュカの気持ちはどうなると思う
how do you think she'd feel?
She might lose her mind.
いよいよ「あっち」に行ってしまうかもしれないぞ
If that happened, could you take care of her?
そうなった時　お前はあいつを支えられんのか？
Even if you could,
支えられたとして　俺たちに撤退命令が出たらどうする
what would you do when we had to withdraw?
俺たちはいつまでも　テュカの心に寄り添ってやれる立場にないんだ
We're not in a position to be her pillars of support forever.
Then you want me to just leave her?
では　このままにしておけと？
ああ　最後まで責任を持てないのなら　何もするな
Yeah.
If you can't see something through to the end,
then don't do anything.
Yes, sir.
分かりました　明日の準備があるので失礼します
I have to get ready for tomorrow, so I'll be going.
I'll see her home.
自分が送っていきます
Drink, idiot.
飲みなさいよぉ　おバカさん
Nine hundred and sixty years, huh?
９６０年…か
It's been an eternity, and yet it's gone by in a flash.
長くもあったし　短くもあったわぁ
I've had countless new meetings,
数え切れないほどの出会いを繰り返し　同じ数だけ別れもあった
and just as many goodbyes.
And I've come through it all.
私はそれを乗り越えてきたけどぉ
Not everybody's as strong as you, Rory.
皆が皆　ロゥリィみたいに強いわけじゃない
Then you don't have to be so cold.
だったら　あんな冷たい言い方しなくても
I don't have enough energy to be nice to everybody.
誰にでも優しくできるほど懐が深くないんでね
Liar.
嘘つき
Listen,
いいこと　懐の定員は一人にしておきなさい
you should direct that energy toward just one person.
You'd be more popular with the ladies.
その方がモテるわよ
You think?
そうか
Girls are happier when they're the only one you're nice to.
優しくしてもらえる唯一の存在になれた方が女は嬉しいのよぉ
You're a nice girl, Rory.
ロゥリィは優しいな
Some "Reaper" you are.
死神なんておっかないあだ名がついてるくせに
死を司るということは　生を司ること
Ruling over death means
ruling over life.
Death is the climax of life.
死とは生の終焉
To have the best death,
最良の死を迎えるには　生きることを尊ばねばならないのよぉ
you must honor life.
You must honor life, huh?
生きることを尊ぶ…か
Yup!
そう
Dola! I'll take some more!
ドーラ　お代わりぃ
Comin' right up!
はい　いいよ
You've had enough.
その辺にしとけよ　潰れても知らねぇぞ
Don't blame me if you pass out.
No! Be nice to me.
いやぁよぉ
優しくしてぇ
Stop it. People are watching.
止せよ　人が見て…
Do you think I care?
私が気にすると思う？
Hey, what's wrong with this place?
おい　なんだこの店は
Does it serve alcohol to children?
この店はガキに酒を飲ますのか？
Thus, the JSDF Fought There!
Hey, wake up, Rory!
おい　起きろよ　ロゥリィ
It's closing time.
もう閉店だってさ
I can't drink anymore.
もう飲めなぁい
Fine.
しょうがねぇな
もっと優しくぅ
Be gentler, please.
Bye.
じゃあな
待ってよぉ
Wait!
Stay with me till morning.
朝まで一緒に　ねぇ　ヨウジ
Okay, Youji?
Oh, fine.
しょうのない奴だ
How dare you...
よくも…
How dare you ruin my plans for the evening!
私のこれからの予定を台無しにしてくれたわねぇ
これからの予定って？
Plans for the evening?
ど…どういうこと…
What's going on?
My name is Yao Ha Dushi.
我が名はヤオ・ハー・デュッシ
A Dark Elf...
ダークエルフ　年は３００歳ってとこかしらぁ
300 years old or so?
What is she thinking?
何考えてんだ　あいつ　死神ロゥリィをガキ呼ばわり？
Calling Rory the Reaper a kid?
It's going to rain blood!
血の雨が降るぞ
What are you doing here?
あなた　何しにここにぃ？
この身はシュワルツの森のデュッシ氏族　デハンの娘
I am the daughter of Dehan of the Clan Dushi,
from the Schwartz Woods.
I've heard that one of the Green People is here,
こちらに「緑の人」がおられると聞き　用件ありて参った次第
and have come to speak to them.
The Green People?
緑の人？
Yes.
おい　そこの男　少女を酔わせて　何を目論んでいる
You there.
Why are you getting a little girl drunk?
You're not some kind of pervert, are you?
まさか　卑劣なことを考えているのではあるまいな
Please, save me!
お願い　助けてぇ
その男が無理矢理お酒を飲ませるのぉ
That man's been forcing me to drink!
"You can't drink my beer?" he shouted, and then he forced me...
俺の酒が飲めないのかって　無理矢理
I knew it!
やはり　そうであったか
Unforgivable.
断じて許せぬ
Rory...
ロゥリィ
Don't worry.
安心するがよい　今すぐこの不埒者を成敗して…
I'll teach him a lesson right now—
あーばよー
Adios!
I'm putting it on your tab!
旦那　お代は付けとくよ
Good, the evildoer has fled.
よし　悪は去った
It's okay now.
もう大丈…
She already climbed out the window.
女も窓から出てったよ
What?
なんと
What an ungrateful child.
礼儀知らずなガキだな　一言ぐらいあっても…
She could've at least—
So what's your order?
で　注文は？
No, I came here to—
いや　ここに来たのは…
There are no Green People here right now.
緑の人なら　もういないよ
This is a tavern.
ここは酒場だ　飲まないんだったら　帰っとくれ
If you won't drink, then leave.
I'll have something to drink, then.
では　酒をもらおう
You're after the Green People, miss?
姉さん　緑の人を訪ねてきたって？
Yes.
You must have a good reason.
訳ありだにゃ？
Meia
I wish to ask a favor.
彼らに頼みたいことがある
Is this why the Priestess put on that act?
使徒様があんな芝居を打った理由はこれか
She has no idea she just drew her sword on one of the guys she's looking for.
まさか剣を向けた相手がお探しの緑の人だなんて
Whatever it is, they may not do it.
Even if that's payback for calling her a kid, that's still awful...
ガキ扱いした仕返しとは言え　気の毒だ
その頼み事は聞いてもらえんかもな
That's right!
そうだにゃあ
Why?
なぜだ
I've heard that they're a noble people.
緑の人は高潔な者たちだと聞いている
So they'd never abandon someone in trouble, right?
ならば　困っている者を見捨てたりはしないのではないか
Of course, I have a reward prepared.
無論　報酬も用意している
信じられん　本物の金剛石だ
I can't believe it! That's real adamantite!
You could buy land and peerage with one that big!
これだけありゃ　爵位が領地付きで買えるぜ
It's huge!
なんてでかさだ
Okay, I'll do it!
よし　その頼み事　俺が…
No, wait! I'll do it!
いや　待て　俺こそ…
Me, too! Me, too!
俺も俺も俺も俺も…
I'm sorry, but I don't think you're up to the task.
申し訳ないが　恐らく諸君らでは力不足だ
What?
なに？
You think so, huh?
言ってくれるな
Then what is it that you want done?
じゃあ　何だってんだ　おめぇさんの頼み事ってのは
I want them to slay a wounded Fire Dragon.
手負いの炎龍退治だ
A... Fire Dragon?
炎…龍
Well? Will you do it?
どうだ　引き受けてくれるか？
If it's not enough,
これでも足りぬと言うのなら
I can offer myself as well.
我が身を捧げることも厭わぬ
A Fire Dragon...
炎龍…
Well...
いや　それは…
Anyway, we'll be going.
じゃ　俺たちはこれで
I hope the Green People take up your offer.
緑の人が引き受けてくれるといいな
No luck, huh?
空振りか
Give up for today.
今日は諦めな
I guess so.
そうする
Where are you staying?
あんた　宿は？
No need to worry about that.
心配無用だ
I can hear the singing of the Wind Spirits.
風の精霊たちの歌声が聞こえる
Untainted air and clean water...
汚れなき空気と清らかな水
The greenery is lush and deep.
緑は深く豊か
This is a good forest.
いい森だ
I'm almost there.
もう少しだ
Just hang in there a little longer, everyone...
もう少しだけ頑張ってくれ　皆
Think you can keep up, Nishimoto?
どうだ
ついて来れるか　西元
後ろにつかれた　右にブレイク
He's behind us! Break right!
Damn it all!
こなくそ
I'm on your tail!
オラー　ケツ奪ったぞ
Not yet...
まだまだ
Those are the Green People!
あれが　緑の人
My clan will be saved.
これで　我が一族は救われる
Fabric, lacquerware, pottery, porcelain, pearls.
反物　漆器　陶器　磁器　真珠
Even Japanese sake!
日本酒なんて物まで
They wouldn't know if we just took one, would they?
Foreign Affairs              Officer Toudou Tetsuo
一本くらいくすねても　分からんよな
Please don't.
やめてくださいよ
In Foreign Affairs, this stuff is ammunition.
これは俺たち外務官僚にとっての武器弾薬なんですから
You say that, but you're drinking it yourself, aren't you?
んなこと言って　自分たちで飲んでんじゃないのか？
We wouldn't do that!
しませんってそんなこと
Alnus Gold
Pieces
Is that your war chest?
こっちは　活動資金か？
Yeah.
ええ　アルヌス協同生活組合から購入した現地通貨です
Local currency provided by the Alnus cooperative.
We'll wine and dine them.
飲ませ　食わす
There are plenty of ways to use it.
使い道はいくらでもありますから
I'm sure that'll work great with a developing country.
発展途上国が相手だと　よく効くだろうな
A dangerous country would use threats
物騒な国だと　こういった賄賂ではなく
instead of bribery like this.
恫喝という手も使うんでしょうけどね
言ってやりゃいい　やれるもんならやってみなって
You should just tell them that if they want a war, we'd be happy to oblige.
そういうわけにはいかないのが外交ってものです
Foreign Affairs doesn't work that way.
We can't make trouble.
下手に波風を立てるわけにはいきません
右　右
Our goal right now is to focus on increasing the number of doves.
今は講和派を増やすのに専念しますよ
Okay! Keep going forward!
よし　そのまま
伊丹　後は任せたぞ
Itami, take care of this for me!
おう　任されて
Yeah, I'm on it!
All right!
よし
To the capital!
いざ帝都へ
Just wait, everyone!
待っていろ　皆
Soon...
すぐに
Soon, I'll bring the Green People!
すぐに緑の人を連れていくからな
unmei niwa sakaraenai ne deatteshimatta
I guess I just can't fight my fate - we've already met!
運命には逆らえないね　出会ってしまった
nani ga aru ka wakaranai keredo
I don't know what might happen,
何があるか分からないけれど　キミと出かけよう
kimi to dekakeyou
but I'm heading out with you!
心おどる遠い景色は　なんだか違って
kokoro odoru tooi keshiki wa
There's something a bit different
nandaka chigatte
about the far off scenery,
doa o akete itsumo no choushi sa
But once we open the door, we're back to
ドアを開けて　いつもの調子さ　どうぞよろしく！
douzo yoroshiku
our usual pace, so let's keep on together!
mada kimerarenai sanpo koosu
We still can't decide which course to walk
まだ決められない散歩コース
iron na mono ga oosugite
There are just too many things to consider.
いろんなものが多すぎて
hikari no uzu ni suikomarete
Pulled into a whirlpool of light,
光のうずに吸い込まれて　まだ迷ってるの？
mada mayotteru no
We're still undecided!
hashirinuketa ano shunkan wa
Amidst a sweet, sweet scent,
走り抜けたあの瞬間は　甘い甘い香りの中で
amai amai kaori no naka de
We can feel a new future within this place.
arata na mirai koko ni kanjiteru
Upon a song, disappearing high into the sky,
新たな未来　ここに感じてる
tondekieru uta ni noseta
But the moment we manage to run on through
飛んで消える歌にのせた　空へ空へきれいな星に
sora e sora e kirei na hoshi ni
I'll cast a spell that sparkle brightly,
キラキラ光るように　魔法かけようから
kirakira hikaru you ni mahou kakeru kara
I'll cast magic which shines bright
Episode 12 What Would Itami Do?
次回　「ゲート」
Next time on GATE:
"What Would Itami Do?"
伊丹なら